

alex.a.adusei@gmail.com +2330549217491

Self-motivated Software Developer | System Engineer with a Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) in Computer Science and Management from Wisconsin International University College with 2 years experience in Software Development, Database Design, Development, and Maintenance, Application Deployment and Payment Integration.

Experienced at communicating with key stakeholders in accessing project needs and managing projects related to software, database and network installation and migration, server visualization, and end user computing.

Officially, my job is to develop enterprise application and databases for small, medium and large organizations. But really, I make the web and mobile users fall in love and addicted to their devices.

I am experienced in web development using PHP, MYSQL, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, TWITTER BOOTSTRAP, CSS3 and HTML 5. I have a working experience with Model View Controller (MVC) and have been involved in maintaining versions of source code using Github. I have also designed and developed web user controls, master pages, validation controls, CSS files using technologies like AJAX Toolkit, Jquery, JavaScript, JSON, and XML.

When working on a new project, I like to speak with my clients so that I can have a clear understanding of their needs and vision of the project. Thank you in advance for your time and consideration. I look forward to working with you soon

# **EDUCATION**

AUG2011 – JUN2015 Bachelor of Arts Computer Science

WISCONSIN INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY COLLEGE

WC

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### MAY2017 – Current Software Developer :: Innovationist

# MICROSOFT APP FACTORY, MOBILE WEB GHANA

Mentored by senior software architects and app developers on how to design, implement and manage complex projects as well as helping me build critical business skills

#### JAN2017 - Current

## Software Development Freelancer

#### **BURGEON CONSULT**

Developing business, market and development strategies and models as well business plans

Writing of business proposals

Communicating with the client to understand their requirements and processes and employing the use of Agile throughout the product development life cycle.

Management of Cloud Dedicated and Shared Servers such as Linode, Heroku, Bluehost, and GoDaddy respectively.

A Tutor at Developers In Vogue Mentor-ship coding boot camp http://developersinvogue.org/

Responsible for the design and creation of Members database for Perez Chapel Int Resurrection Temple.

 $Responsible \ for \ all \ research, \ web \ development \ and \ administration \ http://stockmngr.herokuapp.com/,$ 

http://nellaeffects.com/ http://burgeonconsult.com/ Fotosafe Application for Afro Giant Ltd.

## JUL**2016** - DEC**2016**

### Software Developer and Web Administrator

**SWEN NEWS LTD** 

General IT related duties:

Responsible for Planning and managing software projects, writing of daily and monthly reports to senior management

Managed Windows Web Server, email server and file servers.

Management and review of all ads and web banners/content before they are published.

Responsible for email blasts and social media blasts and user engagement.

Engaged in research to constantly improve and help upgrade the web application to international standards.

Managed MySQL databases using SQL programming language

Coding, implementation, and Integrating of Payment and electronic settlement.

Responsible for all the web development and administration eg: https://swennewsgh.com,

https://accragoodsmarket.com, http://welcome.swennewsgh.com

#### OCT2015 - DEC2015

#### System Engineer

## PROXYNET COMMUNICATION LTD

Analyzed market trends and the competitive landscape to understand opportunities and potential value.

Following instruction and implementing strategies of senior management

Research and learning of cutting edge solution with emphasis on Systems, programming and computer networking

Installation, deployment and configuration of Samsung professional display solutions.

Delivered on-site/in-house IT and technical support for both staff and clients

Procured, installed, configured and maintained the wireless network devices and other system infrastructure

Developed an application called video wall profiler (VWP) for the sales team which reduced the manual Video Wall measurement and evaluation time from 1 day to seconds and also ensured accurate measurement for the deployment of Samsung Enterprise Display solution while increasing customer satisfaction. Moreover, it gave the sales Team the ability to profile more potential clients.

Maintained and monitored systems and web apps to be streamed on Samsung enterprise displays with the aid of magic info URL browser which helped to attract increased and advertised companies brand to potential customers.

# JUL**2013** - OCT**2015**

# Network Engineer

RANA MOTORS & METAL WORKS ENG. CO. LTD

Coached and mentored new staff members

Delivered on-site IT and technical support for staff

Maintained and monitored and troubleshooting of servers, network, staff computers and other System infrastructure

Designed, build and managed wireless and LAN network infrastructure

# **SKILLS**

Database Design and Management

Software development )

Achievement Orientation

Analytical Thinking

Communication (oral)

Communication (written)

Developing Others

PHP MVC MySQL

Laravel Framework

Javascript )

HTML, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, XML

HTML 5, CSS

Java (aj

(ajax) (JSON)

Ubuntu-Linux

Apache Web Server )

**ACHIEVEMENTS** 

Best Student in Picture Making (Visual Arts), Koforidua Secondary School(2006-2007)

JAN**2007** 

In a class of 50 visual arts student, I became the best student in Picture Making. the award was presented to me during the school speech and prize giving day.

# **INTERESTS**

Programming)

(technology)

(Music

Football (learning)

Full Gospel Business Mens Fellowship International